I wish I knew sooner just how small
transistors really are, the electronic
switches inside everything that you use.
Okay, let's start here. This is the size
of the first iPod. And this is the size
of the first transistor.
But we're going so much smaller. This is
the smallest kind of ant, it's only 1
mm. As we get smaller, we approach the
size of one of my favorite animals, the
tardigrade. Now it gets crazy. The
smallest human cell is the red blood
cell. But bacteria are even smaller.
This is the size of the transistor in
that first iPod. Subscribe if this is
already blowing your mind. A flu virus
is about this big. We're almost [music]
there now. This is the size of the
transistors in the first Nintendo Wii.
And if we keep going all the way down,
this is about how small [music] today's
transistors actually are, only a few
nanometers wide. [music] And we're
trying to make them even smaller. If you
want to know how, subscribe.